Michael Martin

Email: michaelhero920@gmail.com

Phone number: 1305 809 7340

Address: 10 Hunt St, Brockton, MA 02302 Brockton, Massachusetts, United States

Summary

I'm a Senior Full Stack Developer with over 10 years of experience in the world of scalable mobile &web applications and platforms, cloud SaaS, Blockchain, and desktop software development..

My specialization is development, optimization and maintenance high traffic web applications using technologies like React, React Native, Redux, Angular 2-9, Ruby on Rails, Python, Django, Gatsby, Next.js, Vue.js, ES6/7, HTML/CSS, Material UI, Styled component, Node, MongoDB, Redis and AWS.

Collaborative and reliable with excellent communications and interpersonal abilities to build rapport with clients, staff, and management, problem solve, and ensure positive customer relations and excellent service.

Experience

Staff Software Engineer

Smarsh • Greater Boston Area

(Nov. 2019 -Dec 2021) Responsibilities:

- Performed initial client assessment and analysis to begin research process.
- Supported Chief Operating Officer with daily operational functions.
- Defined the structure of the Blockchain Development for the Product team and defined the Access controls and security and environment for the Almaty.
- Designed and developed the smart contracts using the Solidity and implemented test scripts on the smart contracts using the truffle framework.
- Optimized the smart contract code and increased the efficiency by 15%, using the Library functionalities of the solidity.
- successfully reached the phase-1 of the Project.

Senior Software Engineer

Wayfair Professional Boston, Massachusetts

(Jul 2017- Aug 2019)

Responsibilities:

- Improved end user experience of Wayfair's in-house application, resulting in an increase of application submissions and total of orders placed by 45%.
- Successfully lead integration of post-order for Wayfair's International Financing product resulting in an increase of orders by 20% within Canada.
- Help support and onboard new hires to the team by sharing knowledge regarding Wayfair's products resulting in a 20% increase in team tasks to be completed.
- Integrate API monitoring through DataDog resulting in improved API response time with 3rd parties by confirming contracted expectations were being met.
- Critically debugged post launch performance issues relating to the loading of site messaging.
- Collaborated with vendors to successfully launch new products and improve API changes.

Full Stack Engineer

MightySignal

(Jan 2014 - Apr 2017)

- Built full-stack projects using React, Redux, Node, Express, Javascript, Typescript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, PostgreSQL.
- Created engaging and responsive front-end applications with React, Redux, Material UI, Bootstrap, HTML & CSS
- Developed server-side applications and APIs with Ruby on Rails
- Automated unit and integration testing with Jest and Jasmine

Web Developer

Marketing Intern Foreign Agricultural Service

(Sep 2012-Dec 2013)

Skills	
--------	--

•	Solidity				Laravel		
•	Geth		Flask 🛮	Solium		Node	
•	Truffle		Typescr	ipt □	React		Go
•	Redux		AWS				
	Python	•		Git/GitLab/Jira/Slack			
	Django						

Education

Eastern Kentucky University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

(Sep2008-Jun 2012)

Languages

□ English(Native)